THE ELUSIVE
SAMURAI
Lord Kunitoki.
It's me, Muneshige.
TOKIYUKI AND KUNITOKI'S UNCLE
Uncle…
What's the state of Kamakura?
And what about Tokiyuki?
I hear Lord Yorishige Suwa
will help Tokiyuki escape.
As for us, let's hurry and leave
at the first light of day.
-Uncle…
-Don't worry.
The lower-ranked samurai
shouldn't know our faces.
I'll deceive them somehow.
You stay hidden.
That's too dangerous!
Lord Takatoki entrusted me with
you, his precious Hojo child.
I will protect you even if
I must lay down my life.
Uncle…
Yes, and above all,
you are my precious little sister's child.
If I fail, please run.
Uncle!
What?
Uncle.
Uncle!
Father!
Everyone!
Lord Tokiyuki. Lord Tokiyuki.
Lord Tokiyuki!
Lord Tokiyuki.
Your face when you're asleep is so sweet.
I could just eat you up.
I know how much you like to
watch children sleep, Father,
-but Lord Tokiyuki is having a nightmare.
-There we go.
Let's see!
I think a peck on the cheek wouldn't hurt.
GLARE
What are you doing? What is wrong with you?
Lord Tokiyuki, I expected as
much from your escaping prowess.
In the future, we call
that a "Wake-up Prank."
PRANK A SUCCESS!!!
I don't care!
This isn't the time to be
playing around, Mr. Yorishige!
You said we could hide in your territory,
but we've just been taking cover
in Kamakura for several days!
That's because the exit of Kamakura
is more tightly guarded than I thought.
We have to be patient until
their watch eases up.
The watch, huh?
I recognize those standards…
But the samurai under those banners, who
had sworn allegiance to the Shogunate,
betrayed us, just like that,
and destroyed Kamakura.
All under Lord Takauji's orders…
To think beneath that kind smile of his,
he was plotting such traitorous plans
to destroy the Shogunate.
Don't worry, Lord Tokiyuki.
In these clothes, we can trick them.
We look like Shinto priests
whose shrine was burned.
Mr. Yorishige.
You told me, "Take back your country
by winning this game of tag
with your excellent ability to run away."
But samurai fight looking straight on.
I've never heard of a samurai taking
a country through a game of tag.
You really think I can
take back this country?
That I can avenge everyone I loved?
-Of course!
-You scared me!
Through my divine eye, I see
a future where you are a hero.
So, Lord Tokiyuki, bear this
burden for a little while longer.
For now…
FUTURISTIC GAME OF DICE
let's play a game of dice while we wait!
Shizuku, prepare the dice and game pieces!
Yes, Father.
I've never seen this game of dice.
What's a God of Poverty?
You'll get to learn when you play.
Come on, Lord Tokiyuki. Join us.
Huh?
I knew I couldn't trust those two.
I have to find who remains
of the Shogunate myself.
Man, there's nothing good here.
One man's trash is another man's trash.
You know, I saw that execution.
Oh, yeah, was it Lord Kunitoki Hojo?
Oh, yeah. The head came clean off.
You have strange taste.
You're lying!
Huh?
Who are you?
There's no way!
My brother… He can't be!
Your brother?
What do you mean your brother?
You're talking about Lord Kunitoki?
Whose kid are you?
I-
This boy is an apprentice at my shrine.
The Hojo family had favored us,
so he can get worked up
hearing Lord Kunitoki's name.
Right?
Yes.
What exactly happened to Lord Kunitoki?
You know, he was entrusted to
his uncle, Muneshige Godaiin.
He was hiding him, but then, he ratted
Kunitoki's hiding spot out to Nitta's men.
AWARD FOR BIGGEST TYRANT 1333
GODAIIN
Having risen to power through his nephew,
Muneshige Godaiin sold
his own flesh and blood,
the regent's nine-year-old son, to
the enemy in the blink of an eye.
The man went on to become one of the most
brutal warlords in Japanese history.
Lord Kunitoki was a Hojo child.
Beheading was his sentence.
I saw it happen earlier.
It was a pitiful death.
Lord Tokiyuki?
Betrayal. Betrayal. Betrayal.
I can't make sense of it.
The Ashikaga family who served
us for generations betrayed us.
Our samurai retainers betrayed us.
And now my own uncle betrayed us.
There's not one person I can trust.
Lord Tokiyuki.
-Lord Tokiyuki.
Lord Tokiyuki!
Did my holy light bring you to your senses?
Why do you keep shining at random times?
I can see it.
I can see a future where Muneshige
Godaiin is sitting down.
You know how I told you I can see
the future with my holy power?
Yeah, a rough vision on rare occasions.
HERE WE GO
GODAIIN - DUMB - ENEMIES
There's a lot of enemy soldiers
around him, and he's well protected.
Where is Uncle now?
Are you curious?
Yes.
In that case…
let's go see.
I'll show you what it means
to win at a game of tag!
Consider avenging your brother…
your first step to reclaiming your country!
Damn it!
Why do you cast me aside?
Don't you know I'm a man
of great military success?
He was a Hojo child!
Is it because he was the
child of a concubine?
The head of a concubine's
child is of no worth to you?
If killing Kunitoki isn't enough
in my life's game of dice,
I need to roll higher numbers.
In that case, maybe I should
aim for the rightful heir!
I can do it.
If I capture Tokiyuki, the true
heir, and present him to them,
everyone will have no choice
but to recognize me!
His demonic behavior drove his friends away.
Seems like he's lost everything.
This greedy brute has turned into a demon
who will chase you to the ends of the earth.
Tokiyuki.
Don't think you can outrun me.
The first sure way to win at the
game of tag is to know your enemy.
Let's go back to the hideout, Lord Tokiyuki.
Huh?
I will bestow upon you the
second sure way to win.
They should be arriving soon.
Right, Father.
It's become easier to win now that we
know what our enemy looks like, right?
Do you not have confidence?
I never took my martial
arts training seriously.
No worries. I have some friends
I want to introduce to you.
They will become your arms and legs.
They will help you greatly
on the battlefield.
KAZUSA PROVINCE - SHIMOSA
PROVINCE - MUSASHI PROVINCE
All right, I'm gonna buy all of Shimosa's
bean fields, getting double the revenue!
Hey, don't pass the God of Poverty to me!
He's about to become the
Emperor God of Poverty too.
I don't think they're
going to be very helpful.
And isn't that a game of
dice from a distant future?
PRODUCER
Hi. It's nice to meet ya, young lord!
My name is Kojiro Nezu. It's a pleasure!
I'm Ayako Mochizuki. Nice
to meet you, my lord.
They are the children of the
Nezu and Mochizuki families,
two families who serve the Suwa family.
And because they serve the Suwa family,
they ultimately serve the
Hojo family above them.
And though both of them are your age, Lord
Tokiyuki, they excel in martial arts.
So please rely on them to avenge our enemy.
I'm Tokiyuki Hojo. Nice to meet you.
-Sir!
What did you think of Lord Tokiyuki?
He's so cute!
I just wanna carry him around.
He's definitely not strong.
And it's a strange proposition
coming from Lord Yorishige
to serve someone whose family
has just been annihilated.
If he's not strong, we have to protect him.
Right.
Now, Lord Tokiyuki, shall we take
on the demon that's after us?
He's coming.
Oh, you look delectable.
Uncle Godaiin?
Oh, Lord Tokiyuki!
If it isn't my lord!
Oh, I'm so glad you're safe.
Lord Yorishige said he would
bring you to safety around Suwa,
so I thought you'd be here.
Are you alone?
Don't worry, your old Uncle
Muneshige's here for you.
Let's run away together.
Uncle.
Yes?
Why did you betray my brother?
Huh?
I see, I see.
-We almost had him!
-My lord!
So you anticipated I would
come looking for you,
and hid some friends to ambush
me to avenge your brother.
You poised yourself as if you trusted
me. It was quite impressive.
To think a child could be so conniving!
But you see, Lord Tokiyuki, the reason
I was entrusted to guard Kunitoki
was not only because I am his
uncle and an important retainer!
I was appointed his guard because I'm strong.
Kill two brats, chop off
your legs, and sell you out.
That's how I'll win my game of dice!
The dice are cast.
Is it a battle or just a game?
It's a turbulent world of
tag with our lives at stake.
This is the first roll!
DEMON OF DICE MUNESHIGE GODAIIN
What happened, Lord Tokiyuki?
This is your chance to avenge your brother!
Get off my lord, scumbag!
You're in my way!
-Hey!
-Damn it.
Take this! Take that!
My lord, get behind me!
I have no openings. And what mighty strength!
I can't do anything while I protect
myself and the Young Lord.
What am I supposed to do
after this, Mr. Yorishige?
After all, we're just kids
going up against a grown man.
If our surprise attack
fails, we stand no chance.
It's just some kiddy sneak attack
with just the three of them.
This is nothing!
I'm quick to adapt to situations.
That's one of my strengths.
I'd betray even my lord's child
if it meant saving my own life!
Don't make it hard for me, Tokiyuki.
Your brother didn't even put up a fight!
Ashikaga overthrew the Shogunate,
and then came tumultuous times.
When the board to the game
of dice has been flipped,
only those who can instantly
adapt can survive!
Hmm?
Tokiyuki!
Tokiyuki, Tokiyuki, Tokiyuki, Tokiyuki!
You're a relic of a bygone era.
Accept your fate, and
fuel my rise to the top!
My lord!
Kojiro, Ayako, retreat!
-Huh?
-Why?
Just listen to me and get back.
You two should take a good
look at this Young Lord.
See who is more adaptable
to tumultuous times.
That's impressive, my lord.
He's seeing through all those swift swings.
And it looks like he's enjoying it.
Those aren't moves you learn by training.
His elusiveness…
It's heaven-sent!
Lord Tokiyuki isn't a coward.
He genuinely enjoys the chase.
One misstep would be fatal.
Capture would be instant death.
His survival instinct is monstrous,
which means his very soul
can find joy in such crisis.
Before the war, back when
Kamakura was peaceful,
the boy was amiable, modest,
kind-hearted, and considerate.
He hated conflict,
and his habit of running away from his
much-despised training was a shortcoming.
He was an ordinary kid like any other.
But on the battlefield, he
becomes a gleeful monster,
happily playing tag against
the fiercest of the fierce.
Shizuku, Kojiro, Ayako, don't you think
it'll be fun to serve a master like that?
A general who's known for running
away? I've never heard of that.
But when you say it like that, Lord
Yorishige, I guess it does sound fun.
I just want to be his friend!
Mm-hmm.
All right, now.
-Go give this another chance!
-Yes, sir!
You mustn't try to protect him.
You have to trust his elusiveness.
The trade-off…
SLUGGISH
-…is his attacks are very
weak. -You little brat!
Go create an opening for him to attack.
If he's set on killing me by evading forever,
then sooner or later…
-You guys!
-Time for offense!
My job isn't to protect the
Young Lord from the enemy.
Tokiyuki!
Whoa.
You bastards!
Try to offer up the enemy
while the Young Lord evades.
Now, my lord!
Brother, Father, citizens of Kamakura,
this head isn't enough to avenge you.
But at least…
it'll make for a souvenir
as you walk your path to the other side!
Huh?
Where did it come from?
I'm not going to be a hero.
Even you're laughing at me.
It's not that I'm making fun of you.
Let's get inside already.
I wonder what's for dinner.
Oh, Tokiyuki!
You can do it!
If you try.
What was that?
You kinda sound like a fraud shaman.
Huh? Really?
It's not a compliment.
I wonder what's for dinner.
I'm hungry for sea bream.
Oh, that sounds good!
EPISODE 3 (YEAR OF 1333):
A FOREST INHABITED BY A GOD
Let's go!